

CFMS 2018-19 President-elect Nominee

Name: Yipeng Ge

School: University of Ottawa

Year of Study: 2/4



Bio/Letter of Intent (250 words max):

Hi CFMS SGM 2018 delegates! My name is Yipeng Ge, and I hope to be your President-Elect. It was an incredibly difficult decision to write this. One of the biggest reasons being, I am deeply cognizant of the weight and caliber of this role; and I hesitate from an awareness of my own comforts, fears, and limitations. However, I recall a time not long ago, that I could not see myself in any such leadership positions, believing that I would not succeed or do a good job knowing that I am a more reflective, introverted, and introspective individual. And yet, here I am, writing this letter of intent for you.

Through time and experience and pushing myself outside my comfort zone, I have learned so very much about myself and CFMS. Learning about myself, I have grown to embrace fear and uncertainty in aim of understanding that challenges and risks facilitate humbleness and compassion in what I do. Learning about CFMS, a truly special organization where I am privileged to represent medical learners, work and learn with passionate students, and advocate on topics that we care deeply about affecting the health of populations. I aim to continue to build capacity for CFMS, empower leadership in others, foster current and new organizational relationships, and continue to be an organization that we are all proud of – one that effectively represents its members, advocates for its members, and our future patients to fully embody our vision, 'Tomorrow's physicians leading for health today".

Yipeng Ge 519.572.5713

Ottawa, ON, Canada <u>yipeng.ge@uottawa.ca</u>

LEADERSHIP AND RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

2017 - 2018	Vice President of Government Affairs: Canadian Federation of Medical Students
	(CFMS)
2017	Chair: 2017 4 th Annual Global Health Students and Young Professionals Summit
	Conference Planning Team
2017 - 2018	Partnerships Co-Lead: Ontario Political Advocacy Committee (OPAC)
2017 - 2018	Liaison: CFMS Representative to Medical Council of Canada (MCC)
2017	Representative: CFMS Delegate to IFMSA March Meeting, SCOPH
2016 - 2017	Coordinator: CFMS Government Affairs and Advocacy Committee (GAAC) Jr.
2016 - 2017	Coordinator: CFMS Local Officer of Global Health Education (LOGHE) Jr.
2016 - 2017	Member: Ontario Political Advocacy Committee (OPAC)
2016 - 2018	Board Member: Canadian Coalition on Global Health Research (CCGHR)
2016 - 2018	Board Member: Canadian Society for International Health (CSIH)
2016	Intern Advocate: World Health Organization Intern Board
2015 - 2018	Reviewer: Hamilton Integrated Research Ethics Board (HiREB)
2015 - 2016	Co-Chair: McMaster Indigenous Health Conference

WORK EXPERIENCE

2016	Internship, World Health Organization Headquarters, Geneva, Switzerland
2014 - 2016	Research Assistant, Population Health Research Institute, Hamilton, ON
2015 - 2016	Teaching Assistant, McMaster University Faculty of Health Sciences, Hamilton, ON
2016	Research Assistant, McMaster Institute for Innovation and Excellence in Teaching and Learning, Hamilton, ON

EDUCATION

2016 - 2020	Doctorate in Medicine, Anglophone stream, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON
2012 - 2016	Bachelor of Health Sciences (Honours) with Specialization in Global Health,
	McMaster University, Hamilton, ON

LANGUAGES

Fluent in English and Mandarin Chinese, beginner in French.

INTERESTS

Athletics: Avid recreational golf player, recreational badminton player, cycling (casually

through the trails in Ottawa), very amateur runner, yoga, squash, bouldering.

Arts: Drawing, sketching, painting, Chinese painting and calligraphy, watercolor painting,

reading and writing.